A Guide to the University of Virginia Board of Visitors Standing and Special Committee Records, 1976, 2002-2008
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
University of Virginia Board of Visitors Standing and Special Committee Records 1976, 2002-2008
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-1/1/3.091
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restricted for ten years from the date of creation. Researchers interested in obtaining access to these records should direct a request in writing to the Office of the Legal Adviser, Madison Hall, University of Virginia. Access to these records will be granted only under the procedures of the Virginia Freedom of Information Act (Code of Virginia -2.1-340 ff.) or if permission is granted by the Secretary of the Board.
Acquisition Information
Use restricted for ten years from the date of creation. Researchers interested in obtaining access to these records should direct a request in writing to the Office of the Legal Adviser, Madison Hall, University of Virginia. Use of these records will be granted only under the procedures of the Virginia Freedom of Information Act (Code of Virginia -2.1-340 ff.) or if permission is granted by the Secretary of the Board.
Scope and Content
The Standing and Special Committee Records of the Board of Visitors Records (ca. 1363 items, 12 boxes) consist chiefly of files of minutes and correspondence from standing and special committees including Audit and Compliance, Buildings and Grounds, Educational Policy, Executive, External Affairs, Finance, Student Affairs and Athletics, Transition, and the University of Virginia's College at Wise as well as the subcommittee on Legislative and Executive Affairs, special committees on Diversity and Governance and the Medical Center Operating Board.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in three series: Series I: General Files of the Board of Visitors, Series II: Campaign Files of the Board of Visitors; and Series III: Restricted Files. Within the series folders are arranged alphabetically by title.
Contents List
- Series I: General Files of the Board of Visitors
  - Arena Fundraising 2003, 9 items (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Audit and Compliance Committee--Correspondence 2005 June-2006 January, 12 items (Box-folder 1:2)
  - Audit and Compliance Committee--Correspondence 2006 March-September, 20 items (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Audit and Compliance Committee--Minutes 2006-2008, 4 items (Box-folder 1:4)
  - Battle, William Cullen 1976-2008, 29 items (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Board Correspondence 1994, 11 items (Box-folder 1:6)
  - Board Meeting 1995 February 13, 1 item (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Board Meeting 2002 July 13, 2 items (Box-folder 1:8)
  - Board Retreat 1999 July-November, 14 items (Box-folder 1:9)
  - Board Retreat 2000, 34 items (Box-folder 1:10)
  - Board Retreat-Folder 1 of 2 2001 June-July, 16 items (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Board Retreat-Folder 2 of 2 2001 July, 23 items (Box-folder 2:2)
  - Board Retreat-Folder 1 of 2 2002 June-July, 19 items (Box-folder 2:3)
  - Board Retreat-Folder 2 of 2 2002 July, 15 items (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee-Correspondence 2005 December-2006 March, 13 items (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee-Correspondence 2006 April-May, 12 items (Box-folder 2:6)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee-Correspondence 2006 June-August, 25 items (Box-folder 3:1)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee-Correspondence 2006 September-December, 27 items (Box-folder 3:2)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee-Meeting 1992 May 22-23, 2 items (Box-folder 3:3)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee-Meeting 1993 February-March, 12 items (Box-folder 3:4)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee-Meeting 1994 August, 6 items (Box-folder 3:5)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee 2005 March, 5 items (Box-folder 3:6)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee-Meetings 2005-2008, 11 items (Box-folder 3:7)
  - Committee Summaries 2006, 2 items (Box-folder 3:8)
  - Committee Summaries 2007, 8 items (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Educational Policy Committee-Correspondence 2005 December-2006 April, 24 items (Box-folder 4:1)
  - Educational Policy Committee-Correspondence 2006 May-September, 19 items (Box-folder 4:2)
  - Educational Policy Committee-Meeting 2002-2005, 14 items (Box-folder 4:3)
  - Educational Policy Committee-Minutes 2002-2008, 9 items (Box-folder 4:4)
  - Executive Committee-Correspondence 2006, 21 items (Box-folder 4:5)
  - Executive Committee-Minutes 2008, 5 items (Box-folder 4:6)
  - External Affairs Committee-Correspondence 2006 January-May, 26 items (Box-folder 4:7)
  - External Affairs Committee-Correspondence 2006 July-2007 October, 17 items (Box-folder 4:8)
  - External Affairs Committee-Minutes 2006-2008, 8 items (Box-folder 5:1)
  - Finance Committee Conference Call 2003 June-July, 6 items (Box-folder 5:2)
  - Finance Committee-Correspondence 2006 January-April, 14 items (Box-folder 5:3)
  - Finance Committee-Correspondence 2006 May-June, 6 items (Box-folder 5:4)
  - Finance Committee-Correspondence 2006 July-December, 13 items (Box-folder 5:5)
  - Finance Committee-Executive Session 1992 May 22, 2 items (Box-folder 5:6)
  - Finance Committee-Meetings 2004-2005, 13 items (Box-folder 5:7)
  - Finance Committee-Minutes 2003-2007, 6 items (Box-folder 5:8)
  - Finance Committee-Minutes 2008, 4 items (Box-folder 5:9)
  - Greer, Thomas Keister 1995-2008, 47 items (Box-folder 5:10)
  - Ivy Road Parking Garage Petition 2002 April-May, 100 items (Box-folder 6:1)
  - Medical Center Operating Board-Correspondence 2006 January-April, 29 items (Box-folder 6:2)
  - Medical Center Operating Board-Correspondence 2006 May, 21 items (Box-folder 6:3)
  - Medical Center Operating Board-Correspondence 2006 July-September, 13 items (Box-folder 6:4)
  - Medical Center Operating Board-Correspondence-Folder 1 of 2 2006 November-December, 15 items (Box-folder 6:5)
  - Medical Center Operating Board-Correspondence-Folder 2 of 2 2006 December, 17 items (Box-folder 6:6)
  - Medical Center Operating Board-Correspondence 2007 January-February, 27 items (Box-folder 6:7)
  - Medical Center Operating Board-Correspondence 2007 March-May, 27 items (Box-folder 7:1)
  - Medical Center Operating Board-Correspondence 2007 July-September, 15 items (Box-folder 7:2)
  - Medical Center Operating Board-Correspondence 2007 October, 26 items (Box-folder 7:3)
  - Medical Center Operating Board-Correspondence 2007 November-December, 32 items (Box-folder 7:4)
  - Medical Center Operating Board-Minutes 2008, 5 items (Box-folder 7:5)
  - Memoranda to the Board 2004, 2006 January-March, 17 items (Box-folder 7:6)
  - Memoranda to the Board 2006 April-August, 37 items (Box-folder 7:7)
  - Memoranda to the Board 2006 September-December, 44 items (Box-folder 8:1)
  - Memoranda to the Former Members of the Board 2005-2006, 8 items (Box-folder 8:2)
  - Memoranda to the Former Members of the Board 2007, 5 items (Box-folder 8:3)
  - Orientation of New Board Members 2002 May 30, 15 items (Box-folder 8:4)
  - Orientation of New Board Members 2003 April 3, 1 item (Box-folder 8:5)
  - Orientation of New Board Members 2004 April 15, 4 items (Box-folder 8:6)
  - Orientation of New Board Members 2005 March 31, 2 items (Box-folder 8:7)
  - Policy Discussion 2006, 4 items (Box-folder 8:8)
  - Preliminary Meeting of the Board 2004-2006, 8 items (Box-folder 8:9)
  - Press 2001-2002, 16 items (Box-folder 8:10)
  - Professorships and Naming 2005 December-2006 January, 16 items (Box-folder 9:1)
  - Professorships and Naming 2006 February-April, 25 items (Box-folder 9:2)
  - Professorships and Naming 2006 June, 13 items (Box-folder 9:3)
  - Professorships and Naming 2006 July-September, 14 items (Box-folder 9:4)
  - Qualchoice 1997-1998, 4 items (Box-folder 9:5)
  - Qualchoice 1999 June-July, 5 items (Box-folder 9:6)
  - Qualchoice 1999 July, 1 item (Box-folder 10:1)
  - Special Committee on Diversity-Correspondence 2006, 23 items (Box-folder 10:2)
  - Special Committee on Diversity-Meeting 2006 March-April, 8 items (Box-folder 10:3)
  - Special Committee on Diversity-Memoranda 2006-2008, 7 items (Box-folder 10:4)
  - Special Committee on Governance-Correspondence 2003, 14 items (Box-folder 10:5)
  - Special Committee on Governance-Meeting 2003 March, 3 items (Box-folder 10:6)
  - Special Meeting of the Board of Visitors 1994 August 22, 10 items (Box-folder 10:7)
  - Student Affairs and Athletics Committee-Correspondence 2005-2006, 28 items (Box-folder 10:8)
  - Student Affairs and Athletics Committee-Meetings 2003-2005, 22 items (Box-folder 10:9)
  - Student Affairs and Athletics Committee-Memoranda 2003-2008, 10 items (Box-folder 10:10)
  - Subcommittee on Legislative and Executive Affairs-Meeting 2005 September, 6 items (Box-folder 10:11)
  - Transition Committee-Minutes 2008, 1 item (Box-folder 10:12)
  - University of Virginia's College at Wise Committee-Correspondence 2006, 13 items (Box-folder 10:13)
  - University of Virginia's College at Wise Committee-Correspondence 2005 March, 3 items (Box-folder 10:14)
  - University of Virginia's College at Wise Committee-Minutes 2005-2008, 7 items (Box-folder 10:15)
- Series II: Campaign Files of the Board of Visitors
  - Campaign for the University of Virginia 1995 October, 14 items (Box-folder 11:1)
  - Campaign Kickoff Invitation List 1995 April 21, 1 item (Box-folder 11:2)
  - Campaign Kickoff Weekend Planning 1994 December-1995 August, 20 items (Box-folder 11:3)
  - Campaign Kickoff Weekend Planning 1995 September-November, 52 items (Box-folder 11:4)
  - Mid-Campaign Celebration 1997 June, 7 items (Box-folder 11:5)
  - Salute to the Campaign 1995 September-October, 19 items (Box-folder 11:6)
- Series III: Restricted Files
  - Greer, Thomas Keister 1982-1996, 3 items (Box-folder 12:1)
  - Ivanov Case 1998-2002, 15 items (Box-folder 12:2)